naturalinsight.com 2018-09-08

# Natural Insight | Privacy Policy

Natural Insight, NI Reveal and Capango are interactive services that can be accessed via the Web, Ni WorkTrak or Capango mobile applications, phone and through transaction gateways (together, the “Services”).The services are provided under their respective brand names by South49 Solutions, Inc. a Delaware corporation. For the purpose of applicable data protection legislation and subject to the following sentence, the data controller of your personal data is South49 Solutions, Inc. at 46040 Center Oak Plaza, Suite 160, Sterling, VA 20166-6595 www.south49.com

Your personal data may be provided to us by our customers or business partners. In such cases, we shall process such personal data as a data processor on behalf of those entities who use our services. In such instances, our customer’s or business partner’s privacy policy, rather than this Policy, will apply to our processing of your personal data.

Our Privacy Policy is designed to maximize your ability to protect your personal, private data while at the same time giving you the opportunity to share and obtain interesting and useful information. This Privacy Policy describes how we treat information received about you when you visit our Services. Please read the Privacy Policy carefully. 

### Information We Collect

**General.** When you register as a user of the Services (each, a “User”) and at other times, we will collect personally identifiable information from you. The personally identifiable information we collect includes limited personal data such as name, address, phone number and email address.  We ask that you not send us, and you do not disclose, any sensitive personal data (e.g., social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, biometrics or genetic characteristics, criminal background or trade union membership) on or through the Services or otherwise to us.   

**Interactive Content.** Because South49 Solutions provides interactive services, other Users may set up work assignments, surveys, order forms, job postings or other mechanisms through which you can be asked to provide certain information. These features are entirely voluntary. If you do not wish to participate, you may elect to not provide the information. South49 Solutions is not responsible for the disclosure or use of any information collected by other Users through the Services; other Users may not be subject to the South49 Solutions privacy policy.

**Usage Information.** Our web services, mobile applications and phone servers automatically collect usage information when you visit our Services. Website usage information is information about our visitors (unregistered users of the Services) and Users that describes how our Services is used and navigated, including the number and frequency of visitors and Users to each web page and the length of their stays. Website usage information also includes the domain names and/or corresponding IP addresses (a numerical identifier for a computer on the Internet) of those who visit our website. Mobile application usage information includes location services data (when authorized on the phone) and photo metadata information (when authorized on the phone). Finally, phone usage information may include caller ID results depending on your local phone company’s ability to transmit that information. To disable caller ID transmissions, please contact your local phone company.

**Device and Connection Information.** We collect information about your computer, phone, tablet, or other devices you use to access the Services. This device information includes your connection type and settings when you install, access, update, or use our Services. We also collect information through your device about your operating system, browser type, IP address, URLs of referring/exit pages, device identifiers, and crash data. We use your IP address and/or country preference in order to approximate your location to provide you with a better Services experience.  How much of this information we collect depends on the type and settings of the device you use to access the Services. 

Security

The personally identifiable information we collect about you is stored in limited access servers. We will maintain appropriate safeguards to protect the security, integrity, and privacy of these servers and of your personally identifiable information. Except as described below, we will not use or intentionally disclose any personally identifiable information about you to any unaffiliated third parties without your consent.

How We Use Information Collected

We will only process your personal data in accordance with applicable data protection and privacy laws. We need certain personal data in order to provide you with access to the Services. If you registered with us, you will have been asked to check a box indicating your agreement to provide this data in order to access our Services or view our content. This consent provides us with the legal basis we require under applicable law to process your data. You maintain the right to withdraw such consent at any time. If you do not agree to our use of your personal data in line with this policy, please do not use our website.  When fulfilling our contractual obligations to our customers (i.e., the data controllers), we have a legitimate interest in processing certain personal data for such contractual purposes.

We may combine the personally identifiable information we collect from you when you use the Services with other information about you that is available to us, including survey information, affiliate and third-party website usage information and information from other sources. We may use such information in several ways, including:

  * To provide you with the goods and services you have requested, and for the purposes disclosed when you provide the personally identifiable information.
  * To send Users email notifications of new Services features and topic-based news alerts if they have signed up for these announcements.
  * To provide you with personalized content.
  * To give South49 Solutions editors information that is useful for developing new features and services that meet Users’ needs.
  * To improve the content and navigation on our Services.
  * To alert you about new products and services and special offers.

We may also share such information with our affiliates and other third parties to provide you with goods or services requested by you. However, any party that receives your information for this purpose will be prohibited from using it for any means other than those necessary to facilitate your transaction with South49 Solutions unless you agree that the party may make other uses of your information.

**Customer support**. We use your information to resolve technical issues you encounter, to respond to your requests for assistance, to analyze crash information, and to repair and improve the Services.

**With your consent**. We use information about you where you have given us consent to do so for a specific purpose not listed above.  For example, we may publish testimonials or featured customer stories to promote the Services, with your permission.

**Automated decision making**.  We may use automated decision-making and/or profiling in regard to your personal data for some services and products, for example when calculating a Ni Score for a user which uses login, scheduling, reporting and work execution information to determine a User rating an employer may consider when offering work assignments. You can request a manual review of the accuracy of an automated decision that you are unhappy with or limit or object to such automated decision-making and/or profiling by contacting us at [support@naturalinsight.com](mailto:support@naturalinsight.com)

**Other uses**.  Finally, we may also use personally identifiable information to enforce our Terms and Conditions of Use or share such information with i) the issuer of a criminal or civil subpoena; ii) governmental authorities when legally required to do so; or iii) governmental authorities investigating a crime. We reserve the right to contact you at any time regarding Services-related problems or questions as well as changes to our Terms and Conditions of Use, our Privacy Policy, or other policies that affect you and your use of our Services.

Your Rights in Your data

**Opt Out.** You can notify us that you do not wish to receive information about new products and services and special offers by opting out at the time you enter your personally identifiable information on the NaturalInsight.com website or by emailing us at [support@naturalinsight.com](mailto:support@naturalinsight.com).

**Opt In.** Several of the services we provide, including many of the email notifications and the surveys we conduct, are entirely voluntary. You will not receive such services unless you opt in, i.e., unless you expressly choose to receive these services.

**Access.** You may access the data we hold about you at any time via your profile/account, by contacting your employer if they have provided you with our services or by contacting us directly.

**Amend.** You can also contact us to update or correct any inaccuracies in your personal data.

**Erase and forget.** In certain situations, for example when the data we hold about you is no longer relevant or is incorrect, you can request that we erase your data.

### Cookies

We employ cookie technology to help visitors and Users move faster through the website portion of the Services. When a visitor or User accesses a South49 Solutions website and takes advantage of certain features, we place several cookies on that User’s computer. A cookie is a string of information sent by a website and stored on your hard drive or temporarily in your computer’s memory. This allows the website to recognize you as you move through the website without having to keep asking you for your username and password.  
  
---  
  
**Type of cookies**

| 

**Purpose**  
  
**_Essential Cookies_**

| 

These cookies are essential to provide you with services available through our website and to enable you to use some of its features. For example, they allow us to retain your secure connection to our servers as you interact with our site. Without these cookies, the services that you have asked for cannot be provided, and we only use these cookies to provide you with those services.  
  
**_Functionality Cookies_**

| 

These cookies allow our website to remember choices you make when you use our website, such as remembering your language preferences and remembering the changes you make to other parts of our website which you can customize. The purpose of these cookies is to provide you with a more personal experience and to avoid you having to re-enter your preferences every time you visit our website.  
  
**_Analytics and Performance Cookies_**

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about traffic to our website.  The information gathered does not identify any individual visitor.  The information is aggregated and anonymous. We use this information to help operate our website more efficiently, to gather broad demographic information and to monitor the level of activity on our website. 

We use Google Analytics and other third party analytics services for this purpose. Google Analytics uses its own cookies.  It is only used to improve how our website works.  You can find out more information about Google Analytics cookies here: <https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies>.  You can find out more about how Google protects your data here: [www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html).

You can prevent the use of Google Analytics relating to your use of our website by downloading and installing the browser plugin available via this link:  <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>  
  
**_Social Media Cookies_**

| 

These cookies are used when you share information using a social media sharing button or “like” button on our website or you link your account or engage with our content on or through a social networking website such as Facebook, Twitter, or Google+.  The social network will record that you have done this.   
  
### Review and Correction

You may review and update the personal information you provide us with as part of the registration process, or unsubscribe from the Services, by accessing your Profile or calling us directly at (800) 961-5203.

### Links

We may make content from affiliated or other third party resources, including other websites, available to you from links located on the Services. These resources are not subject to our Privacy Policy, and may have their own individual privacy policy. We recommend that you review the privacy policy at each such resource to determine how it protects your privacy.

Policy Modifications

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will post any changes here, so be sure to check back periodically.

### How we store and secure information we collect

#### **  
Transfer of information**

Your data, including personal data that we collect from you, may be transferred to, stored at and processed by us and our affiliates outside the country in which you reside, including, but not limited to the United States, where data protection and privacy regulations may not offer the same level of protection as in other parts of the world. By using our website and services, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this policy.

#### **Information storage and security**

We use data hosting services providers in the United States and Germany to host the information we collect, and we use technical measures to secure your data. 

While we implement safeguards designed to protect your information, no security system is impenetrable and due to the inherent nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that data, during transmission through the Internet or while stored on our systems or otherwise in our care, is absolutely safe from intrusion by others.

#### **How long we keep information**

How long we keep information we collect about you depends on the type of information, as described in further detail below.  After such time, we will either delete or anonymize your information or, if this is not possible (for example, because the information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your information and isolate it from any further use until deletion is possible. 

Account information: We retain your account information for as long as your account is active and a reasonable period thereafter in case you decide to re-activate the Services.  We also retain some of your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, to enforce our agreements, to support business operations, and to continue to develop and improve our Services. Where we retain information for Services improvement and development, we take steps to eliminate information that directly identifies you, and we only use the information to uncover collective insights about the use of our Services, not to specifically analyze personal characteristics about you. 

Information you share on the Services: If your account is deactivated or disabled, some of your information and the content you have provided will remain in order to allow your company or other users to make full use of the Services. 

**Managed accounts:** If the Services are made available to you through an organization (e.g., your employer), we retain your information as long as required by the administrator of your account. 

**Marketing information** : If you have elected to receive marketing emails from us, we retain information about your marketing preferences for a reasonable period of time from the date you last expressed interest in our Services, such as when you last opened an email from us or ceased using your account.  We retain information derived from cookies and other tracking technologies for a reasonable period of time from the date such information was created.  

### Legal Bases for Processing (for EEA users)

If you are an individual in the European Economic Area (EEA), we collect and process information about you only where we have legal bases for doing so under applicable EU laws.  The legal bases depend on the Services you use and how you use them. This means we collect and use your information only where:

  * We need it to provide you the Services, including to operate the Services, provide customer support and personalized features and to protect the safety and security of the Services;
  * It satisfies a legitimate interest (which is not overridden by your data protection interests), such as for research and development, to market and promote the Services and to protect our legal rights and interests;
  * You give us consent to do so for a specific purpose; or
  * We need to process your data to comply with a legal obligation.

If you have consented to our use of information about you for a specific purpose, you have the right to change your mind at any time, but this will not affect any processing that has already taken place.  Where we are using your information because we or a third party (e.g. your employer) have a legitimate interest to do so, you have the right to object to that use though, in some cases, this may mean no longer using the Services.

### Other Important Privacy Information

#### **Notice to End Users**

Many of our products are intended for use by organizations. Where the Services are made available to you through an organization (e.g. your employer), that organization is the administrator of the Services and is responsible for the accounts and/or Services sites over which it has control. If this is the case, please direct your data privacy questions to your administrator, as your use of the Services is subject to that organization's policies. We are not responsible for the privacy or security practices of an administrator's organization, which may be different than this policy.

Administrators are able to:

  * require you to reset your account password;
  * restrict, suspend or terminate your access to the Services;
  * access information in and about your account;
  * access or retain information stored as part of your account;
  * install or uninstall third-party apps or other integrations

In some cases, administrators can also:

  * restrict, suspend or terminate your account access;
  * change the email address associated with your account;
  * change your information, including profile information;
  * restrict your ability to edit, restrict, modify or delete information

Please contact your organization or refer to your administrator’s organizational policies for more information.

### Comments and Question

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

South49 Solutions, Inc.  
46040 Center Oak Plaza, Suite 160  
Sterling, Virginia 20166

info@South49.com.

_This policy was last updated on May 22, 2018._
